#### 1 ####
Ord{end}

#### 2 ####
Tyrana{end}

#### 3 ####
Zosen{end}

#### 4 ####
Johto{end}

#### 5 ####
Wind Chronos Tower{end}

#### 6 ####
Nidosand{end}

#### 7 ####
Colossia{end}

#### 8 ####
Morzine{end}

#### 9 ####
Saccuda{end}

#### 10 ####
Sand Chronos Tower{end}

#### 11 ####
Makka{end}

#### 12 ####
Mt. Ebon{end}

#### 13 ####
Kryna{end}

#### 14 ####
Yached{end}

#### 15 ####
Fire Chronos Tower{end}

#### 16 ####
Keihi{end}

#### 17 ####
Trulit{end}

#### 18 ####
Zensen{end}

#### 19 ####
Semerzo{end}

#### 20 ####
Ice Chronos Tower{end}

#### 21 ####
Naga Invasion Port{end}

#### 22 ####
Naga (Ground Lv.){end}

#### 23 ####
Naga (Mid Lv.){end}

#### 24 ####
Naga (Upper Lv.){end}

#### 25 ####
Naga (Top Lv.){end}

#### 26 ####
???{end}

#### 27 ####
Secret Island 1{end}

#### 28 ####
Secret Island 2{end}

#### 29 ####
Secret Island 3{end}

#### 30 ####
Secret Island 4{end}

#### 31 ####
Limit Cut{end}

#### 32 ####
Limit Break{end}

#### 33 ####
Secret Conversation{end}

#### 34 ####
Pilot Mode{end}

#### 35 ####
Music - "Rodea"{end}

#### 36 ####
Music - "Prototype"{end}

#### 37 ####
Luxury Liner Decor{end}

#### 38 ####
Orthos Body{end}

#### 39 ####
Rylus Body{end}

#### 40 ####
Kelvis Body{end}

#### 41 ####
Valghis Body{end}

#### 42 ####
Dark Rodea{end}

#### 43 ####
Unlock Ticket Islands{end}

#### 44 ####
Ticket 1{end}

#### 45 ####
Ticket 2{end}

#### 46 ####
Ticket 3{end}

#### 47 ####
Ticket 4{end}

#### 48 ####
Ticket 5{end}

#### 49 ####
Ticket 6{end}

#### 50 ####
Ticket 7{end}

#### 51 ####
Ticket 8{end}

#### 52 ####
Upgrade Armor{end}

#### 53 ####
Power Upgrade{end}

#### 54 ####
Speed Upgrade{end}

#### 55 ####
Fly Ability Upgrade{end}

#### 56 ####
Sp. Ability Upgrade{end}

#### 57 ####
Ammo Upgrade{end}

#### 58 ####
Imp. Reload Time{end}

#### 59 ####
Rapid Fire{end}

#### 60 ####
Imp. Slide Time{end}

#### 61 ####
Imp. Cooldown{end}

#### 62 ####
Add Ability{end}

#### 63 ####
Imp. Lock-On{end}

#### 64 ####
Imp. Cooldown{end}

#### 65 ####
Imp. Range{end}

#### 66 ####
Armor{end}

#### 67 ####
Power{end}

#### 68 ####
Speed{end}

#### 69 ####
Flight Ability{end}

#### 70 ####
Special Ability{end}

#### 71 ####
Ammo Upgrade{end}

#### 72 ####
Imp. Reload Time{end}

#### 73 ####
Rapid Fire{end}

#### 74 ####
Imp. Slide Time{end}

#### 75 ####
Imp. Cooldown{end}

#### 76 ####
Add Ability{end}

#### 77 ####
Imp. Lock-On{end}

#### 78 ####
Imp. Cooldown{end}

#### 79 ####
Imp. Range{end}

#### 80 ####
Base Specs{end}

#### 81 ####
Special Ability{end}

#### 82 ####
M. Gun Gear{end}

#### 83 ####
Slide Gear{end}

#### 84 ####
Lock-On Gear{end}

#### 85 ####
Fastest Clear Time{end}

#### 86 ####
Total Play Time{end}

#### 87 ####
Gravitons Obtained{end}

#### 88 ####
Total Chain Count{end}

#### 89 ####
Total Combo Count{end}

#### 90 ####
Flight Count{end}

#### 91 ####
Boost Attack Count{end}

#### 92 ####
Wall Jump Count{end}

#### 93 ####
Landing Count{end}

#### 94 ####
Damage Received Count{end}

#### 95 ####
Miss Count{end}

#### 96 ####
Total Enemy KO's{end}

#### 97 ####
Machine Gun KO's{end}

#### 98 ####
Boost Attack KO's{end}

#### 99 ####
Lock-On Gear KO's{end}

#### 100 ####
Slide Gear KO's{end}

#### 101 ####
Total Flight Distance{end}

#### 102 ####
Normal Flight Travel Distance{end}

#### 103 ####
Boost Attack Travel Distance{end}

#### 104 ####
Ground Travel Distance{end}

#### 105 ####
Total Steps Walked{end}

#### 106 ####
Comment{end}

#### 107 ####
%d{end}

#### 108 ####
%d{end}

#### 109 ####
%d{end}

#### 110 ####
%d km{end}

#### 111 ####
%d steps{end}

#### 112 ####
R{end}

#### 113 ####
O{end}

#### 114 ####
D{end}

#### 115 ####
E{end}

#### 116 ####
A{end}

#### 117 ####
Whoa! That's amazing, Rodea! I can't
believe you cleared it so fast!{end}

#### 118 ####
I knew you could do it, Rodea! I bet
the mech soldiers are so scared!{end}

#### 119 ####
It's okay, Rodea! This is
still above average!{end}

#### 120 ####
It's okay, Rodea!
I'm still on your side!{end}

#### 121 ####
Hmm... I'm sure you're trying...
Yeah, I think you did your best...{end}

#### 122 ####
I'm impressed! How far do you
plan to go, Rodea?{end}

#### 123 ####
Amazing, Rodea! I wonder how many
times you can fly around Garuda?{end}

#### 124 ####
Was that about average? No way,
right? You're Rodea, after all.{end}

#### 125 ####
That wasn't very good, Rodea.
I think even I could catch up.{end}

#### 126 ####
I think you can do better than
that, Rodea.{end}

#### 127 ####
Wow! You'll wipe out those mech
soldiers in no time!{end}

#### 128 ####
This is the Play Log!{end}

#### 129 ####
If you keep destroying these mech
soldiers, Naga's gonna notice...{end}

#### 130 ####
{end}

#### 131 ####
You did it! But you gotta defeat
more or Garuda will get taken over!{end}

#### 132 ####
You haven't been beaten at all!
Hopefully this doesn't get worse.{end}

#### 133 ####
{end}

#### 134 ####
I think you're getting hit too much,
but since you're getting repairs...{end}

#### 135 ####
{end}

#### 136 ####
Whoa! That's a high number! I'm
surprised you can keep moving!{end}

#### 137 ####
Wow, I'm surprised! You must be
some kinda genius, Rodea!{end}

#### 138 ####
Whoa! That's a really high number!
But can't it go even higher?{end}

#### 139 ####
That's amazing, Rodea!
Keep it up!{end}

#### 140 ####
You're getting there, but you still
have a long way to go!{end}

#### 141 ####
Hm, this is a little low, but not
bad starting out!{end}

#### 142 ####
Whoa! This might cover Garuda's
energy needs for a while!{end}

#### 143 ####
So many! This might be more herbs
than I've ever collected!{end}

#### 144 ####
You collected a lot! Too bad there's
no reward for it, huh?{end}

#### 145 ####
Wow! Impressive! But you're far
from over! Let's collect more!{end}

#### 146 ####
We still have a long way to go!
Collect as many as you can!{end}

#### 147 ####
Which record do you want to see,
Rodea?{end}

#### 148 ####
Select PAD{end}

#### 149 ####
BGM Volume Settings{end}

#### 150 ####
SE Volume Settings{end}

#### 151 ####
Voice Volume Settings{end}

#### 152 ####
Movie Volume Settings{end}

#### 153 ####
Auto Aim Sensitivity{end}

#### 154 ####
Ion's Chattiness{end}

#### 155 ####
Subtitles{end}

#### 156 ####
Camera{end}

#### 157 ####
GamePad Display{end}

#### 158 ####
BGM Volume Settings{end}

#### 159 ####
SE Volume Settings{end}

#### 160 ####
Voice Volume Settings{end}

#### 161 ####
Movie Volume Settings{end}

#### 162 ####
Auto Aim Sensitivity{end}

#### 163 ####
Ion's Chattiness{end}

#### 164 ####
{end}

#### 165 ####
Subtitles{end}

#### 166 ####
Gyro{end}

#### 167 ####
Save and Exit{end}

#### 168 ####
Reset to Default{end}

#### 169 ####
You can change the volume settings here
for background music. Simply move the
cursor to adjust the volume.{end}

#### 170 ####
You can change the volume settings here
for sound effects that play when you fly,
pick up items, take damage, etc.{end}

#### 171 ####
You can change the volume settings here
for voices. The Ionceiver is useful, but
it can be a little noisy...{end}

#### 172 ####
You can change the volume settings for
movies here. Set the volume level to
whatever level you prefer.{end}

#### 173 ####
You can adjust the auto aim sensitivity
settings here. Auto aim is useful, but
too much sensitivity can be a problem!{end}

#### 174 ####
You can adjust how often Ion talks here.
Ion will constantly talk at the maximum
setting. You've been warned...{end}

#### 175 ####
{end}

#### 176 ####
Subtitles can be turned ON/OFF here.
This affects movie subtitles only. Feel
free to set this to whatever you want.{end}

#### 177 ####
Turn the gyro function ON/OFF. While it's
on, you can control the camera by tilting
the 3DS.{end}

#### 178 ####
The settings can be reset to their
default state here.{end}

#### 179 ####
Any changes to the settings can be
saved here.{end}

#### 180 ####
I think it can be improved further, but
something's missing...{end}

#### 181 ####
I think I upgraded this as much as I can!
I don't want to make things worse, so how
about we work on something else instead?{end}

#### 182 ####
Aww! You don't have enough materials!{end}

#### 183 ####
Your armor can be upgraded here!
As your armor's level increases, you'll
be able to withstand more attacks!{end}

#### 184 ####
You can upgrade your armor to Lv. 3! It's
not too strong yet, but hang in there!
Each increase will make you even tougher!
{end}

#### 185 ####
Wanna upgrade your armor to Lv. 4? Your
armor has properties that I've never seen
before! I'm still figuring it out!{end}

#### 186 ####
You can upgrade your armor to Lv. 5!
I think you're getting stronger! Feel
free to thank my gut instinct for that!{end}

#### 187 ####
You should upgrade your armor to Lv. 6!
Naga's got nothing on your power! But if
they have this tech, why are they...?{end}

#### 188 ####
A Lv. 7 armor upgrade is available! Did
you know that your cogs and screws look
just like the ones we make on Garuda?{end}

#### 189 ####
Your armor can be upgrade to Lv. 8 now!
I think I might be a genius! Don't you
think so too, Rodea? ...Well, don't you?{end}

#### 190 ####
I can upgrade your armor to Lv. 9... I
think... I'll just tinker with this and
then...oops! I-It's nothing! Don't worry!{end}

#### 191 ####
The final armor upgrade! Lv. 10! You've
become so strong, Rodea! I can tell since
we've been fighting together for so long.{end}

#### 192 ####
Upgrade your power here! This will make
your Boost Attack stronger. Y'know, that
thing where you spin around and charge!{end}

#### 193 ####
You can upgrade your power to Lv. 3! It's
hard to beat enemies when your power is
low. Upgrade it and go kick some butt!{end}

#### 194 ####
You wanna upgrade your power to Lv. 4?
Doesn't all that spinning make you dizzy?
Then again, you are a robot...{end}

#### 195 ####
You can now upgrade your power to Lv. 5!
Do you feel stronger? Who knew you had
so many parts that could be modified...{end}

#### 196 ####
Lv. 6 power upgrade available! Are these
upgrades changing your Boost Attack's
color, or are you doing that yourself?{end}

#### 197 ####
You can upgrade your power to Lv. 7 now.
Your Boost Attack is, like, zoooooooooom!
Don't you think? Zoom, zoom, zoooooooom!{end}

#### 198 ####
A Lv. 8 power upgrade is available. You
can already KO most enemies in one hit,
but there's still room for improvement.{end}

#### 199 ####
You can upgrade your power to Lv. 9, but
can you even handle it? I don't want you
break yourself with a Boost Attack...{end}

#### 200 ####
The final power upgrade! Lv. 10! It must
have been tough to collect all those mech
pieces... Thanks for your hard work!{end}

#### 201 ####
Upgrade your speed to fly faster! But you
burn energy based on the distance flown,
so your fuel efficiency won't change...{end}

#### 202 ####
Upgrade your speed to Lv. 3! There are
lots of perks to flying faster such as
getting to places quicker, and, um...{end}

#### 203 ####
You wanna upgrade your speed to Lv. 4?
At that speed, you'll leave the Ion Wave
in the dust! Wait...that's bad for me...{end}

#### 204 ####
You can upgrade your speed to Lv. 5!
Flying too fast makes things harder to
control, but you'll get to places faster.{end}

#### 205 ####
You wanna upgrade your speed to Lv. 6?
Hey, what's it like to fly? Does the wind
feel good? I wanna fly like you, Rodea...{end}

#### 206 ####
Your speed can be upgraded to Lv. 7.
Honestly, I have no idea what I'm doing
when I perform these upgrades.{end}

#### 207 ####
You can upgrade your speed to Lv. 8.
Being fast is convenient, but it's hard
too! Have you been able to control it? {end}

#### 208 ####
Now you can upgrade your speed to Lv. 9.
What do you think about while you're
flying, Rodea? I'm dying to know...{end}

#### 209 ####
You can upgrade your speed to Lv. 10!
This is the final upgrade! I don't think
I could handle going this fast...{end}

#### 210 ####
This function is called the Dolphin
Maneuver! While you're flying, you can
go in an arc all whoosh! It's amazing!{end}

#### 211 ####
If there are any enemies under you while
landing with a Fast Dive, the Dive Attack
function will let you crush 'em like BAM!{end}

#### 212 ####
With the Swallow Reversal function, you
will automatically attack if you use a
Boost Attack after dodging an attack!{end}

#### 213 ####
While landing with a Fast Dive, the Sonic
Dive function will let you attack nearby
enemies with a disasterrific shockwave!{end}

#### 214 ####
With the Tail Clip function, if you hold
down the flight button when you hit a
wall, you can cling to it!{end}

#### 215 ####
The Dash function will increase your walk
speed! But be careful! Once you select
this upgrade, it can't be undone.{end}

#### 216 ####
The Tail Clip Extension will increase the
cling duration of the Tail Clip! You like
the name? I'm trying something new here.{end}

#### 217 ####
This upgrade will increase your ammo with
the Machine Gun Gear! More bullets equals
more blam-blam, so upgrade this often!{end}

#### 218 ####
It's nice to have lots of bullets so you
don't have to wait around for ammo to
recover. Plus, it's super satisfying!{end}

#### 219 ####
You can still increase your ammo size.
What do you think of my upgrade skills?
I think they're easier to use now.{end}

#### 220 ####
This is the last ammo upgrade. Your
bullet count can't get any higher, so
you'll need to rely on your skills now.{end}

#### 221 ####
This upgrade will make your bullets
recover faster. You can't shoot if you're
out of ammo, so time your shots wisely!{end}

#### 222 ####
You can improve your reload speed even
more! However, it's better to manage your
bullets wisely so you don't run out.{end}

#### 223 ####
This upgrade is convenient, but I dunno
if you should rely on it all the time...
Oh well, it's still fun to upgrade!{end}

#### 224 ####
This is the last reload time upgrade.
Ammo won't recover any faster now, so
the rest is up to your skill!{end}

#### 225 ####
The Rapid Fire upgrade will increase your
rate of fire! I think... Um, this should set
it to Triple Burst! Most likely...{end}

#### 226 ####
With this last upgrade, you should be
able to fire on Full Auto! Don't worry!
Yeah, that's it! Trust my gut instinct!{end}

#### 227 ####
This upgrade will increase your slide
time! It pairs great with Multi Slide!
It won't work with slide panels, though.{end}

#### 228 ####
Remember, this doesn't affect your slide
from a slide panel. It's also pointless
if you don't know how to Multi Slide.{end}

#### 229 ####
I already mentioned it twice so I won't
repeat myself, but just upgrade wisely.
Also, have you learned Multi Slide yet?{end}

#### 230 ####
Here's a fun little fact--sliding is
actually faster than flying, as long as
there's ground to actually slide on...{end}

#### 231 ####
You can improve your slide's cooldown
here? Hm? What's a cooldown? It helps you
recover slide energy faster...I think?{end}

#### 232 ####
With this upgrade, your slide energy will
recover even faster! Don't underestimate
how much I love tinkering.{end}

#### 233 ####
Is it more convenient to have faster
slide recovery? I can't tell because
I've never done a slide before.{end}

#### 234 ####
This is the last upgrade to improve your
slide cooldown. I hope you've been making
good use of these, Rodea.{end}

#### 235 ####
The Multi Slide function will let you
slide on the ground. Just Boost Attack
toward the ground to get your slide on!{end}

#### 236 ####
The Sonic Boom function will let you
damage enemies you pass by using the
Multi Slide! Isn't that amazing!?{end}

#### 237 ####
This upgrade will increase the number of
targets you can lock on to at once.{end}

#### 238 ####
You want the Improve Lock-On upgrade,
right? I'm on it! It must be awesome to
have lots of enemies targeted at once!{end}

#### 239 ####
Use this Lock-On upgrade to target your
enemies, then take 'em out with a boom!
Or a bang-bang if that's more your thing!{end}

#### 240 ####
The last Improve Lock-On upgrade! Are
you getting the hang of the Lock-On Gear?
I think Gears will help you out a lot.{end}

#### 241 ####
Using the Lock-On Gear uses up energy,
but this Improve Cooldown upgrade should
make it recover faster...I think.{end}

#### 242 ####
The Lock-On Gear lets you lock on to
enemies, but only when you're releasing
Lock-On energy...um, I think.{end}

#### 243 ####
The Lock-On Gear seems useful at first
glance, but its low attack power actually
makes it pretty hard to use...{end}

#### 244 ####
How's your Lock-On energy recovery speed?
It should be much faster now! It's not
a placebo, I swear!{end}

#### 245 ####
The Improve Range upgrade improves your
Lock-On Gear range. This will help you
lock on to more enemies!{end}

#### 246 ####
Let's expand your range with the Improve
Range upgrade! Wait, I'm not pushing
upgrades on you! I swear!{end}

#### 247 ####
You can fly in an arc. 

[Using the Dolphin Maneuver]
Immediately after selecting a flight
destination with the A Button, press
the Left Stick in any direction.{end}

#### 248 ####
Fast Dive now deals damage.

[Using the Dive Attack]
This effect is automatically applied
when you perform a Fast Dive.{end}

#### 249 ####
Counterattack after a Snap Roll.

[Using the Swallow Reversal]
During the Snap Roll, while Rodea is
in slow motion, press the B Button.{end}

#### 250 ####
Fast Dive unleashes a shockwave.

[Using the Sonic Dive]
This effect is automatically applied
when you perform a Fast Dive.{end}

#### 251 ####
You can cling to walls and ceilings.

[Using the Tail Clip]
Hold the A Button before you fly into
an object. There is a time limit to
how long you can cling to surfaces.{end}

#### 252 ####
Your walking speed has increased.

[Using Extend Movement]
Once acquired, this effect is
automatically applied.{end}

#### 253 ####
Your Tail Clip duration increases.

[Using the Tail Clip EX]
Once acquired, this effect is
automatically applied.{end}

#### 254 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 15."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
upgrade to Lv. 5. Good luck...{end}

#### 255 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 20."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
upgrade to Lv. 9. I'm rooting for you!{end}

#### 256 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear All Stages."
If you unlock this, new dialogue lines
will appear throughout the game.{end}

#### 257 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 5."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
play in FPS mode. How exciting...!{end}

#### 258 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear All Stages."
You'll be able to change the stage music
to "Music - Rodea." Hope you enjoy it...{end}

#### 259 ####
The prerequisite is "Obtain 6000
Gravitons." You'll be able to change
the stage music to "Music - Prototype."{end}

#### 260 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 5."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
make decorations in the Upgrade Area...{end}

#### 261 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 8."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
play as Orthos. Isn't his name Olme...?{end}

#### 262 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 13."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
play as Rylus. Oh my, it's that fairy...{end}

#### 263 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 18."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
play as Kelvis. She's your sister, right?{end}

#### 264 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 24."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
play as Valghis. Turn, turn, turn...{end}

#### 265 ####
The prerequisite is "Defeat All Hidden
Enemies." If you unlock this, you can
change your clothes. Looking snazzy...{end}

#### 266 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Stage 5."{end}

#### 267 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket
Islands."{end}

#### 268 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 1."{end}

#### 269 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 2."{end}

#### 270 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 3."{end}

#### 271 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 4."{end}

#### 272 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 5."{end}

#### 273 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 6."{end}

#### 274 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 7."{end}

#### 275 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 15."{end}

#### 276 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 20."{end}

#### 277 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear All Stages."{end}

#### 278 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 5."{end}

#### 279 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear All Stages."{end}

#### 280 ####
The prerequisite is "Obtain 6000
Gravitons."{end}

#### 281 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 3."{end}

#### 282 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 8."{end}

#### 283 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 13."{end}

#### 284 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 18."{end}

#### 285 ####
The prerequisite is "Clear Chapter 24."{end}

#### 286 ####
The prerequisite is "Defeat All Hidden
Enemies."{end}

#### 287 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 5."
If you unlock this, you'll be able to
go to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 288 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock StreetPass
Islands." If you unlock this, a new isle
will be added to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 289 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 1."
If you unlock this, a new isle will be
added to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 290 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 2."
If you unlock this, a new isle will be
added to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 291 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 3."
If you unlock this, a new isle will be
added to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 292 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 4."
If you unlock this, a new isle will be
added to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 293 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 5."
If you unlock this, a new isle will be
added to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 294 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 6."
If you unlock this, a new isle will be
added to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 295 ####
The prerequisite is "Unlock Ticket 7."
If you unlock this, a new isle will be
added to the Ticket Islands.{end}

#### 296 ####
Now you can upgrade to Lv. 5.
Good luck...{end}

#### 297 ####
Now you can upgrade to Lv. 9.
I'm rooting for you!{end}

#### 298 ####
New lines of dialogue will appear in
various places. Please keep an ear out
for them...{end}

#### 299 ####
Now you can play in FPS mode. I heard
it's dynamic and dramatic...{end}

#### 300 ####
You can change the stage music to
"Music - Rodea." Please sing along
and enjoy.{end}

#### 301 ####
You can change the stage music to
"Music - Prototype." It's a very
nice song.{end}

#### 302 ####
You can create decorations for the Ion
Wave in the Upgrade Area... It's like
a dream come true...{end}

#### 303 ####
You can play the game as Orthos.
But what about little Olme...?{end}

#### 304 ####
You can play the game as Rylus.
Don't I know that fairy...?{end}

#### 305 ####
You can play the game as Kelvis.
I didn't know you had a sister.{end}

#### 306 ####
You can play the game as Valghis.
Maybe you'll get to turn some keys...{end}

#### 307 ####
Your outfit will change.
Oh my, what nice clothing...{end}

#### 308 ####
The Ticket Islands have been unlocked.{end}

#### 309 ####
Ticket 1 has been unlocked.{end}

#### 310 ####
Ticket 2 has been unlocked.{end}

#### 311 ####
Ticket 3 has been unlocked.{end}

#### 312 ####
Ticket 4 has been unlocked.{end}

#### 313 ####
Ticket 5 has been unlocked.{end}

#### 314 ####
Ticket 6 has been unlocked.{end}

#### 315 ####
Ticket 7 has been unlocked.{end}

#### 316 ####
Ticket 8 has been unlocked.{end}

#### 317 ####
Congratulations...
You unlocked it...{end}

#### 318 ####
Mr. Rodea, you seem to be
a little short...{end}

#### 319 ####
Unfortunately, you don't meet the
requirements...{end}

#### 320 ####
It's been turned ON...
Please try it out...{end}

#### 321 ####
It's been turned OFF...
What a shame. Maybe next time...{end}

#### 322 ####
A piece of iron scrap! Basically, it's
a hunk of broken mech parts. It's super
hard cuz it's made of iron! Rock solid!{end}

#### 323 ####
This isn't any old piece of scrap. It's
got metal plating, y'know! It's shiny!
Wait, what kind of plating is this?{end}

#### 324 ####
Steel is harder than iron. It's an alloy 
made from different metals! That's why 
this scrap is hard, yet flexible.{end}

#### 325 ####
Platinum is a silver-white metal. It's
extremely stable and doesn't melt or
rust. Well, to a point, that is!{end}

#### 326 ####
Wow! I've never seen such high-quality
scrap metal! It's super durable and
shiny! This metal is truly diamond-class.{end}

#### 327 ####
This is...a screw made of iron. Yep!
No mistaking it! I know a screw made of
iron when I see one!{end}

#### 328 ####
Long ago, there was a famous blacksmith
named Noff Osada. He devoted his life
to forging this screw.{end}

#### 329 ####
This is a screw made of steel. A BIS
screw is even smaller than normal
screws. Well? Are you impressed?{end}

#### 330 ####
I can't believe it! A platinum screw?
What a feat of engineering! Wait, why
would Naga make platinum screws anyway?{end}

#### 331 ####
What is this!? It's huge! And so hard!
But lightweight, too! I can't tell what
it's made of! I love mysterious junk!{end}

#### 332 ####
Did you know that iron cogs like this are
used to transfer kinetic energy? You can
use multiple cogs to move big machines!{end}

#### 333 ####
A chrome plated cog. Chrome is a very
peculiar metal. It changes into different
colors when it oxidizes.{end}

#### 334 ####
It's hard to process titanium, even I
have trouble doing it. Yet this cog is
so meticulously shaped... Impressive...{end}

#### 335 ####
How pretty! You might think cobalt is a
blue color, but I think I read somewhere
that pure cobalt actually looks silver...{end}

#### 336 ####
Hmm, I dunno what this cog is... I can't
guess what it's made of or where it was
manufactured. I just know it's old...{end}

#### 337 ####
Iron wire is very versatile. You can use
it to tie things together, twist it into
a thicker wire, or shape it into barbs!{end}

#### 338 ####
Copper wire is more flexible than iron
wire, so it's easier to work with. It
also looks really pretty when polished!{end}

#### 339 ####
Steel wires are really tough, but they're
known for being easy to work with. I feel
like I can make anything with this!{end}

#### 340 ####
This wire is so thin... I don't get it.
Why does Naga insist on waging war when
they have amazing technology like this?{end}

#### 341 ####
Hm? What is this? It's soft, but it's
stretchy and won't tear. I think I could
do a lot of useful things with this!{end}

#### 342 ####
A shaft is basically a stick. So an iron
shaft is an iron stick. Simple enough,
but it's a very useful component.{end}

#### 343 ####
A chrome plated shaft. The chrome makes
it more resistant to rust. It's useless
if it gets scraped off, though...{end}

#### 344 ####
Aluminum is light but it's softer than
titanium, so it's harder to use. I hope
we find some kinda super metal one day...{end}

#### 345 ####
Titanium is sturdy so it's great for
making frames. In the future, I hope the
exterior alone can function as a frame.{end}

#### 346 ####
A mystery material! Something's written
on it... "Fye-burr Ree-in-forsed Plaz-
tick"... What the heck is this?{end}

#### 347 ####
I use this glass for the Ion Wave's
windows and stuff. It's really good for
dispersing light throughout the ship!{end}

#### 348 ####
Despite its name, this glass isn't that
much harder. It diffracts light rather
than dispersing it.{end}

#### 349 ####
U-Umm... This is... "R-Refractive index"?
"Distribution"? "O-Optical device with
multiple lenses"? What the heck is this!?{end}

#### 350 ####
This lens uses electron rays instead of
light, but I dunno what that even means.
It lets you see really well, though!{end}

#### 351 ####
X-rays are amazing! I heard you can use
them to see really small objects or even
through walls, but I have no idea how.{end}

#### 352 ####
Hm, I think this is a device for moving
stuff, but I have no idea how it works!
It looks as old as you, Rodea...{end}

#### 353 ####
{end}

#### 354 ####
{end}

#### 355 ####
{end}

#### 356 ####
{end}

#### 357 ####
What is this? It's like some kinda board,
but there's a bunch of wiring and some
weird stone on it. Should we test it out?{end}

#### 358 ####
{end}

#### 359 ####
{end}

#### 360 ####
{end}

#### 361 ####
{end}

#### 362 ####
I don't know what this is at all! There's
copper wires in a square box, and I think
there's electricity running through it!{end}

#### 363 ####
{end}

#### 364 ####
{end}

#### 365 ####
{end}

#### 366 ####
{end}

#### 367 ####
{end}

#### 368 ####
Dolphin Maneuver{end}

#### 369 ####
Dive Attack{end}

#### 370 ####
Swallow Reversal{end}

#### 371 ####
Sonic Dive{end}

#### 372 ####
{end}

#### 373 ####
Tail Clip{end}

#### 374 ####
Extended Movement{end}

#### 375 ####
Tail Clip EX{end}

#### 376 ####
Armor{end}

#### 377 ####
Power{end}

#### 378 ####
Speed{end}

#### 379 ####
Ammo Upgrade{end}

#### 380 ####
Imp. Reload Time{end}

#### 381 ####
Rapid Fire{end}

#### 382 ####
Dolphin Maneuver{end}

#### 383 ####
Dive Attack{end}

#### 384 ####
Swallow Reversal{end}

#### 385 ####
Sonic Dive{end}

#### 386 ####
Imp. Slide Time{end}

#### 387 ####
Imp. Cooldown{end}

#### 388 ####
Add Ability{end}

#### 389 ####
Imp. Lock-On{end}

#### 390 ####
Imp. Cooldown{end}

#### 391 ####
Imp. Range{end}

#### 392 ####
Tail Clip{end}

#### 393 ####
Extended Movement{end}

#### 394 ####
Tail Clip EX{end}

#### 395 ####
This value indicates the toughness
of your armor. The higher the value,
the more attacks you can endure.

This benefit automatically takes
effect when leveled up.{end}

#### 396 ####
This value indicates the power of
your Boost Attack. The higher the
value, the more damage it will deal.

This benefit automatically takes
effect when leveled up{end}

#### 397 ####
This value indicates your flight
speed. The higher the value, the
faster you travel while flying.

This benefit automatically takes
effect when leveled up{end}

#### 398 ####
Leveling this increases your Machine
Gun Gear ammo. As you gain more
ammo, your shots will consume less
Gear energy, allowing you to fire
more bullets! Don't ignore the value
of energy efficiency!{end}

#### 399 ####
Leveling this increases your Gear
energy recovery after firing the
Machine Gun Gear. If you run out
of Gear energy and need to recover,
this might save you in a pinch.{end}

#### 400 ####
Leveling this increases the Machine
Gun Gear's fire rate. It's an easy
weapon to use, but the shots don't
pack much of a punch. The Rapid
Fire upgrade compensates for that
weakness.{end}

#### 401 ####
This function will let you fly in an
arc. Boost Attacks will be stronger
while you fly in an arc.
[Controls] - Select a spot with the
A Button to fly toward it, then tilt
the Left Stick in any direction.{end}

#### 402 ####
Stomp enemies beneath you while
performing a Fast Dive. This effect
occurs automatically.
[Controls] - Press the Y Button + Down
to perform a Fast Dive.{end}

#### 403 ####
Strike back at an attacker and deal
huge damage. Only usable after dodging
an attack with the Snap Roll.
[Controls] - During a Snap Roll, press
the B Button while you're in slow motion.{end}

#### 404 ####
Release a shockwave when landing with
a Fast Dive, damaging nearby enemies.
This effect occurs automatically.
[Controls] - Press the Y Button + Down
to perform a Fast Dive.{end}

#### 405 ####
Leveling this increases the duration
of the Slide Gear, allowing you to use
your Gear energy more efficiently.
Keep in mind that using a slide panel
to slide will not consume Gear energy.{end}

#### 406 ####
Leveling this will make your consumed
Slide Gear energy recover faster. Even
if you use all your energy, you'll be
able to slide again after a short time.{end}

#### 407 ####
Adds various effects to your slide.
[Level 2] Multi Slide
Use a Boost Attack toward the ground
to slide without a slide panel.
[Level 3] Sonic Boom
Damage nearby enemies while sliding.{end}

#### 408 ####
Leveling this will let you target
more enemies with the Lock-on Gear.
Keep in mind that you can't perform
any other actions while you're locked
on to a target.{end}

#### 409 ####
Leveling this will make your consumed
Lock-on Gear energy recover faster,
allowing you to lock on to targets
more reliably.{end}

#### 410 ####
Leveling this increases the range of
the Lock-on Gear. At first, you can
only lock on to targets near the
reticle. But as the range increases,
you'll be able to lock on to distant enemies.{end}

#### 411 ####
You can cling to objects you collide
with while flying. While clinging,
your flight energy will recover.

[Controls] - Fly into an object you've
targeted while holding the A Button. {end}

#### 412 ####
Increases your walk speed.

[Controls] - This benefit automatically
takes effect.{end}

#### 413 ####
Increases the time limit on the Tail
Clip function, allowing you to cling
to objects for a longer period of time.

[Controls] - This benefit automatically
takes effect.{end}

#### 414 ####
Status{end}

#### 415 ####
Upgrade Area{end}

#### 416 ####
Play Log{end}

#### 417 ####
Unlock Area{end}

#### 418 ####
Options{end}

#### 419 ####
Title{end}

#### 420 ####
Ticket Isles{end}

#### 421 ####
Luxurious Chair{end}

#### 422 ####
Cozy Bed{end}

#### 423 ####
Scholarly Desk{end}

#### 424 ####
Fancy Mug{end}

#### 425 ####
Wrench-like Tool{end}

#### 426 ####
Versatile Toolbox{end}

#### 427 ####
Rodea Plushy{end}

#### 428 ####
Princess Plushy{end}

#### 429 ####
FM Detector{end}

#### 430 ####
Crab Vacuum{end}

#### 431 ####
Humidifier{end}

#### 432 ####
Metal Plant{end}

#### 433 ####
Proof of Glory{end}

#### 434 ####
Tonio's Gratitude{end}

#### 435 ####
{end}

#### 436 ####
Sorry, I can't handle that yet.{end}

#### 437 ####
I can't make that yet...{end}

#### 438 ####
The Ion Wave shakes a lot, but this chair
is made of metal and it's bolted to the
floor. Perfect!{end}

#### 439 ####
Nothing beats a fluffy bed! I've been
using a sleeping bag on the floor, so
sometimes I get a backache!{end}

#### 440 ####
It's nice to have a desk for drawing up
blueprints! I know I use my gut, but I
do draw blueprints sometimes, you know?{end}

#### 441 ####
I'm usually on the Ion Wave so I enjoy
having basic necessities like cups.
Plus, a personal mug seems so fancy!{end}

#### 442 ####
I've been wanting a heavy-duty tool. I
think a big tool will help me make your
upgrades and modify the Ion Wave...{end}

#### 443 ####
My tool collection keeps getting bigger,
but my old toolbox is full. I kinda want
a new one...{end}

#### 444 ####
What do you think?
I think it's pretty nice.{end}

#### 445 ####
She's a princess from a picture book that
I read as a child. Grandpa says she's my
ancestor, but...I wonder if that's true.{end}

#### 446 ####
This is really useful! Now we can fly
even without windows! In theory, that
is...{end}

#### 447 ####
Presenting Mr. Tidy! This miraculous
machine will sweep and clean up after
you! I should make it right away!{end}

#### 448 ####
The Naga mech soldiers are scary, but
they're kinda cute, don't you think?
Maybe I have the same taste as Geardo...{end}

#### 449 ####
A pleasing airship filled with machines!
Sonia once told me that taking care of
plants is a wonderful feeling...{end}

#### 450 ####
A lot of people in Garuda aren't good
with machines. If we had invention
contests, I know I'd take first place!{end}

#### 451 ####
Tonio wrote a letter thanking me for
everything, so I'm gonna make a frame
and hang it up!{end}

#### 452 ####
{end}

#### 453 ####
Hehe. Whaddaya think? Comfy-looking chair, right?
I'm gonna sit here and watch the skies at my leisure.
But if I'm watching the sky, who's piloting the ship?{end}

#### 454 ####
I made a bed! Finally, an upgrade from that old
sleeping bag! No more sleeping on the cold floor!
...Wait, I still have to sleep in HERE!?{end}

#### 455 ####
You like it? Desks have culture, don't you
think? I'm gonna draw all my blueprints here!
Wait, when have I ever drawn blueprints...?{end}

#### 456 ####
I made a coffee mug. Nothing beats soaring
through the skies with some coffee in hand.
Whoa! Almost spilled some!{end}

#### 457 ####
I wanted some big tools, so I made some.
It's a giant wrench-looking...thing. I'll
get lots of use out of this! I think...{end}

#### 458 ####
My old toolbox wasn't cutting it, so I made
a new one. You can't tell by looking at it,
but it's a multi-purpose toolbox!{end}

#### 459 ####
What do you think? Cute, right? It's a huggably
soft Rodea doll! Plus, it comes with a Graviton
energy detection function!{end}

#### 460 ####
A princess of a ruined country...in doll form!
She's from the picture books I read as a child.
She's so beautiful, and yet she looks so sad, too.{end}

#### 461 ####
Check this out! Isn't it amazing? I applied the
same principles as Mr. Detecto to make it. It
utilizes frequency modu... Ah bit mah tongue...{end}

#### 462 ####
To create a pleasant living space, I made a
crab-model vacuum cleaner for the busy Ion
Wave! Cleaning is a piece of cake with this.{end}

#### 463 ####
A pleasant life starts with clean air! So I
made an air purifier. The air on the ship
feels so much cleane-- *cough cough*{end}

#### 464 ####
Even though we're surrounded by machinery, I think
it's important to remember that Garuda is full of
nature! That's why I made a plant...out of screws!{end}

#### 465 ####
I made this for you since you've been working
so hard, but I'm not sure if you'll like it. I heard
they used to regift this stuff in the past.{end}

#### 466 ####
Tonio drew a flower circle for me so I made
a frame for it. What's a flower circle anyway?{end}

#### 467 ####
{end}

#### 468 ####
StreetPass Islands{end}

#### 469 ####
StreetPass Encounters{end}

#### 470 ####
Until next island is unlocked{end}

#### 471 ####
All unlocked{end}

#### 472 ####
Distribution Island{end}

#### 473 ####
A new island was distributed!{end}

#### 474 ####
No new distributions{end}

#### 475 ####
{end}

#### 476 ####
StreetPass Islands{end}

#### 477 ####
Distribution Island{end}

#### 478 ####
StreetPass Comm.{end}

#### 479 ####
Internet Comm.{end}

#### 480 ####
You can go to the StreetPass Islands from
here! There are lots of mech pieces to
find there! Let's go check it out, Rodea!{end}

#### 481 ####
You can go to Distribution Island from
here! The island changes periodically
so don't forget to check it out!{end}

#### 482 ####
You can turn StreetPass Communication
ON/OFF! The islands expand as you
StreetPass with more people!{end}

#### 483 ####
You can turn the Network Connection
ON/OFF! While ON, a unique island will
be sent when you enter the Lost Islands!{end}

#### 484 ####
Checking StreetPass Comm. data.{end}

#### 485 ####
Checking Distribution data.{end}

#### 486 ####
Data check complete.{end}

#### 487 ####
Saving data to SD card.{end}

#### 488 ####
{end}

#### 489 ####
StreetPass data for this software
is not registered.{end}

#### 490 ####
StreetPass cannot be activated for any
more software titles on this system.
Go to StreetPass Management in the
System Settings and deactivate
StreetPass for some other title.{end}

#### 491 ####
You must delete StreetPass Comm.
data for this software.{end}

#### 492 ####
Program error.{end}

#### 493 ####
Invalid ID.{end}

#### 494 ####
You must delete messages or you will
exceed data capacity.{end}

#### 495 ####
Temporarily unable to gain access due to
Busy status or other issues. Retrying
may resolve this issue.{end}

#### 496 ####
Failed to delete.{end}

#### 497 ####
Could not create instance.{end}

#### 498 ####
Did not agree to Terms of Service.{end}

#### 499 ####
Disabled due to Parental Controls.{end}

#### 500 ####
Internet Connection has ended.{end}

#### 501 ####
Save data is corrupted. Please restart
the game and delete the save data, then
create a new game.{end}

#### 502 ####
Could not recognize SD card.{end}

#### 503 ####
There was an error in the save data.{end}

#### 504 ####
Task quenching count is 0 (Necessary
deletion task.).{end}

#### 505 ####
Not initialized.{end}

#### 506 ####
Failed to connect.{end}

#### 507 ####
Data retrieval error.{end}

#### 508 ####
No save data found.{end}

#### 509 ####
SD card is set to disable saving.{end}

