#### 1 ####
Things are heating up in the sky.
Let's stay on the ground for now.{end}

#### 2 ####
Not that way!{end}

#### 3 ####
Looks like the battle in the sky is
finished. I can head up there now.{end}

#### 4 ####
I should jump and enter pre-flight
mode to make sure things are safe.{end}

#### 5 ####
I gotta make sure it's safe first.{end}

#### 6 ####
Safety confirmed. Exiting pre-flight
mode. Entering flight mode.{end}

#### 7 ####
During pre-flight, aim the reticle
at your destination and press jump.{end}

#### 8 ####
Princess Cecilia should be where
the rainbow marker is.{end}

#### 9 ####
The gauge around the reticle is
the flight energy indicator.{end}

#### 10 ####
It will be gradually consumed
during flight, so be careful.{end}

#### 11 ####
Flight energy can be restored by
landing or by obtaining Gravitons.{end}

#### 12 ####
If I'm out of flight energy, I can
use Gravitons as fuel in a pinch.{end}

#### 13 ####
The number at the bottom left is my
Graviton supply.{end}

#### 14 ####
But they're not very fuel efficient,
so be careful with them.{end}

#### 15 ####
Gh! More enemies!?{end}

#### 16 ####
My armor energy at the lower left
will decrease as I receive damage.{end}

#### 17 ####
Don't let it run out, or I'll earn
a "Miss."{end}

#### 18 ####
My spare parts are to the lower
left. If they run out...Game Over.{end}

#### 19 ####
Remember, 100 Gravitons will restore
one of these spares.{end}

#### 20 ####
Let's get rid of these enemies and
keep going. Use a Boost Attack!{end}

#### 21 ####
Let's enter pre-flight mode
to get airborne.{end}

#### 22 ####
While flying, press the attack
button to do a Boost Attack.{end}

#### 23 ####
Point to an enemy and fly at it!
Then press the attack button!{end}

#### 24 ####
Using a Boost Attack will consume
extra flight energy, so be careful.{end}

#### 25 ####
Even if the reticle is slightly off
target, auto-aim will correct it.{end}

#### 26 ####
Don't stop! Keep going!{end}

#### 27 ####
After a Boost Attack, you can press
the attack button mid-spin to chain{end}

#### 28 ####
another Boost Attack, but this
drains flight energy, so be careful.{end}

#### 29 ####
Okay, the path is clear! The rainbow
marker is my next destination!{end}

#### 30 ####
The Snap Roll is a special maneuver
I can use while flying.{end}

#### 31 ####
Using it will allow me to evade
enemy attacks by spinning.{end}

#### 32 ####
But remember, once you use it, you
can't use it again for a short time.{end}

#### 33 ####
Now, let's talk about charging. It's
good for flying to specific spots.{end}

#### 34 ####
Hold down the jump button and I'll
immediately start to charge.{end}

#### 35 ####
Move the reticle to select a target,
then release the button to fly.{end}

#### 36 ####
But be careful, there's a limit
to how long I can hold a charge.{end}

#### 37 ####
All right, just a little more to go!{end}

#### 38 ####
Princess Cecilia... I'll be there
soon.{end}

#### 39 ####
Is that...? It is!
Princess Cecilia!!!{end}

#### 40 ####
This debris is blocking the door...
Let's shatter it!{end}

#### 41 ####
Gh! One attack won't do anything...
I'll just have to keep attacking!{end}

#### 42 ####
This is the wrong way!
I need to go help the Princess!{end}

#### 43 ####
Rodea! Watch out for the mech
soldiers' attacks!{end}

#### 44 ####
When an enemy is targeting you, an
alert will appear around you!{end}

#### 45 ####
You'll get hit once the needle
display makes a full rotation!{end}

#### 46 ####
So try to dodge before that!{end}

#### 47 ####
The Tail Clip function was
installed!{end}

#### 48 ####
If you fly into a wall and hold the
jump button, you'll cling to it!{end}

#### 49 ####
You can't cling to walls forever
though, so be careful!{end}

#### 50 ####
The Dolphin Maneuver function
was installed!{end}

#### 51 ####
If you use the Circle Pad right
after pressing the jump button,{end}

#### 52 ####
If you use the Control Stick right
after pressing the jump button,{end}

#### 53 ####
If you wave the remote right
after pressing the jump button,{end}

#### 54 ####
If you move the Left Stick right
after pressing the jump button,{end}

#### 55 ####
You'll zoom in an arc toward the
specified direction!{end}

#### 56 ####
You'll zoom in an arc toward the
direction you waved!{end}

#### 57 ####
The Fast Attack function was
installed!{end}

#### 58 ####
Your attacks will auto-target the
nearest enemy, even while walking!{end}

#### 59 ####
The Swallow Reversal function
was installed!{end}

#### 60 ####
Press the attack button after you
dodge an attack with the Snap Roll!{end}

#### 61 ####
But you have to dodge at the last
second. Better start practicing!{end}

#### 62 ####
Oh, I almost forgot. I installed
a lock-on function on you!{end}

#### 63 ####
Press the focus button on Mr. Detecto
to track nearby enemies.{end}

#### 64 ####
It's useful against enemies who
try to give you the slip!{end}

#### 65 ####
Use it well!{end}

#### 66 ####
The Multi-Slide function was added!
Slide pads are a thing of the past!{end}

#### 67 ####
Try flying into the ground or
walls with a Boost Attack!{end}

#### 68 ####
Also, you can change directions
during a slide as easy as walking!{end}

#### 69 ####
But only slightly, though.{end}

#### 70 ####
This is the Upgrade Area! You can
spend mech pieces for upgrades!{end}

#### 71 ####
Get powered up here and take out
Naga with a bang!{end}

#### 72 ####
Oh, but be careful! Upgrades are
permanent and irreversible!{end}

#### 73 ####
Welcome to the Unlock Area...{end}

#### 74 ####
You can unlock all kinds of special
content here using Legacy Medals...{end}

#### 75 ####
Unlocked content is always active
unless it needs to be turned on...{end}

#### 76 ####
There are lots of different things
to unlock, so be careful...{end}

#### 77 ####
This is where I can make items to
decorate the Ion Wave's interior!{end}

#### 78 ####
I can make things with mech pieces.
But once made, it can't be unmade!{end}

#### 79 ####
Welcome to Multiplayer! You can
play with your friends here!{end}

#### 80 ####
Select the number of players.{end}

#### 81 ####
Choose a stage to play.{end}

#### 82 ####
Welcome, Rodea!
This is the Play Log!{end}

#### 83 ####
This is where all the records you
set are kept!{end}

#### 84 ####
Some records are cool, others not
so much, so check them all out!{end}

#### 85 ####
If you're in the air, or just want to survey
your surroundings, quickly ascend by
pressing the Y Button.{end}

#### 86 ####
To quickly descend, press Down on
the Left Stick and press the Y Button
at the same time.{end}

#### 87 ####
Press the Y Button to ascend, and press
the Y Button + Down on the Left Stick to
descend. Test it out in different areas.{end}

#### 88 ####
If you aim the reticle at a target and
quickly press the B Button after using
a Boost Attack,{end}

#### 89 ####
you can perform a Chain Attack.{end}

#### 90 ####
By pressing the B Button again after a Chain
Attack, you can follow it up with another
Chain Attack.{end}

#### 91 ####
Press the B Button right after jumping to
automatically perform a Boost Attack at the
nearest target.{end}

#### 92 ####
Try it out when you want to attack a nearby
enemy or crystal.{end}

#### 93 ####
You can open the Menu Screen by pressing
the Y Button in the World Map.{end}

#### 94 ####
In the Menu Screen, you can upgrade
Rodea's functions or unlock secret
content. Be sure to use it often!{end}

#### 95 ####
You can fly high by using the rocks that
rise up when Odeon attacks.{end}

#### 96 ####
Hold the B Button while you have 50 or more
Gravitons to use Shining Bullet.{end}

#### 97 ####
While Shining Bullet is active, you can
defeat nearby enemies by repeatedly
pressing the B Button.{end}

#### 98 ####
Here are some free Gravitons so you can
try it out.{end}

#### 99 ####
Press the ZR Button to target a nearby enemy.{end}

#### 100 ####
Press the ZR Button again to switch to
standard camera mode.{end}

#### 101 ####
If you press the B Button while Rodea is on
the ground, he will execute a Quick Attack,
which targets nearby enemies and objects.{end}

#### 102 ####
Let's destroy the debris blocking the
airship door with a Quick Attack.{end}

#### 103 ####
About Rodea's Additional Functions:
You can select a Gear by pressing
Up or Down on the +Control Pad.{end}

#### 104 ####
How to Use the Machine Gun Gear:
Select it with the +Control Pad and
press the X Button to use it.{end}

#### 105 ####
There are different ways to use a Gear
depending on what it is. Experiment with
different methods when you get one.{end}

#### 106 ####
Welcome to the Ticket Islands. There are
treasures hidden throughout each island
here.{end}

#### 107 ####
The mech soldiers have hidden the treasures,
so defeat them to get the loot.{end}

#### 108 ####
Islands that have treasure are marked with
a green marker, so you should focus your
search on those areas.{end}

#### 109 ####
Text (temporary){end}

#### 110 ####
Text (temporary){end}

#### 111 ####
Text (temporary){end}

#### 112 ####
Text (temporary){end}

#### 113 ####
Text (temporary){end}

#### 114 ####
Move{end}

#### 115 ####
Jump{end}

#### 116 ####
Enter Pre-flight{end}

#### 117 ####
Reticle Control{end}

#### 118 ####
Boost Attack{end}

#### 119 ####
Snap Roll{end}

#### 120 ####
Hold to Charge{end}

#### 121 ####
(Reserve){end}

#### 122 ####
Gear Change{end}

#### 123 ####
Target Enemy{end}

#### 124 ####
Chain Attack{end}

#### 125 ####
Fast Rise{end}

#### 126 ####
Fast Fall{end}

#### 127 ####
Jump{end}

#### 128 ####
To a Nearby Target{end}

#### 129 ####
Required Materials{end}

#### 130 ####
Move Cursor{end}

#### 131 ####
Unlock Status{end}

#### 132 ####
Prerequisites{end}

#### 133 ####
Release Lock{end}

#### 134 ####
Required Materials{end}

#### 135 ####
Move Cursor{end}

#### 136 ####
Hear Comment{end}

#### 137 ####
Press both to release{end}

#### 138 ####
Shining Bullet{end}

#### 139 ####
Open Menu{end}

#### 140 ####
Press both to target{end}

#### 141 ####
to target{end}

#### 142 ####
to release{end}

#### 143 ####
Quick Attack{end}

#### 144 ####
Select Gear{end}

#### 145 ####
Machine Gun Gear{end}

