#### 1 ####
And so, Naga's invasion of Garuda{end}

#### 2 ####
came to an end.{end}

#### 3 ####
Amid the flames of war, Princess{end}

#### 4 ####
Cecilia, who was presumed missing,{end}

#### 5 ####
was rescued by her bodyguard, Rodea,{end}

#### 6 ####
and claimed her throne. {end}

#### 7 ####
Peace returned to Garuda and Naga.{end}

#### 8 ####
In her later years, the princess{end}

#### 9 ####
listens as Rodea tells her stories{end}

#### 10 ####
about her free-spirited descendant,{end}

#### 11 ####
1000 years in the future.{end}

#### 12 ####
A gentle but determined princess,{end}

#### 13 ####
and an energetic inventor who soars{end}

#### 14 ####
freely through the skies.{end}

#### 15 ####
With the promises he made to those{end}

#### 16 ####
two nestled in his heart, Rodea{end}

#### 17 ####
slowly closes his eyes.{end}

