#### 1 ####
Welcome to the StreetPass Islands!
What kind of treasure will you find?{end}

#### 2 ####
The destination is on the radar. The
green marker will guide you, too!{end}

#### 3 ####
Be sure to pick up the items after
you defeat the machine soldiers.{end}

#### 4 ####
If you don't, the items will vanish
and be gone for good!{end}

#### 5 ####
Good job, Rodea! Get all of 'em?
The Ion Wave will take us back!{end}

#### 6 ####
Welcome to the StreetPass Islands!
What kind of treasure will you find?{end}

#### 7 ####
Be sure to pick up the items after
you defeat the machine soldiers.{end}

#### 8 ####
If you don't, the items will vanish
and be gone for good!{end}

#### 9 ####
The destination is on the radar. The
green marker will guide you, too!{end}

#### 10 ####
Good job, Rodea! Get all of 'em?
The Ion Wave will take us back!{end}

