#### 1 ####
1,000 years ago...{end}

#### 2 ####
The terrestrial civilization known{end}

#### 3 ####
as the Naga Empire faced a severe energy crisis.{end}

#### 4 ####
As the Empire's demise drew near, Emperor Geardo{end}

#### 5 ####
discovered a new energy source located in Garuda,{end}

#### 6 ####
a floating continent in the sky.{end}

#### 7 ####
Coveting Garuda's energy, Emperor Geardo prepared{end}

#### 8 ####
an invasion to be launched when the two continents{end}

#### 9 ####
overlap--which occurs only once every 1,000 years.{end}

#### 10 ####
Princess Cecilia, daughter of Geardo, was{end}

#### 11 ####
distraught over this selfish war of aggression.{end}

#### 12 ####
"Once Garuda drifts beyond Naga's sky, the{end}

#### 13 ####
invasion will have no choice but to cease."{end}

#### 14 ####
And so, Princess Cecilia prayed for Garuda to{end}

#### 15 ####
move out of harm's reach as soon as possible...{end}

#### 16 ####
Emperor Geardo, however, planned to use an ancient{end}

#### 17 ####
artifact known as the Key of Time to create a gate{end}

#### 18 ####
that would connect the two continents.{end}

#### 19 ####
When Princess Cecilia learned of her father's{end}

#### 20 ####
plan, she and her royal bodyguard, Rodea, took{end}

#### 21 ####
the Key of Time and fled.{end}

#### 22 ####
Eluding capture, the two almost made it to Garuda.{end}

#### 23 ####
But Geardo's forces managed to intercept them.{end}

#### 24 ####
Undeterred, Princess Cecilia gave half of the{end}

#### 25 ####
Key of Time to Rodea and sent him to the distant{end}

#### 26 ####
land of Garuda.{end}

#### 27 ####
And so, 1,000 years later...{end}

